Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: President Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Lowell Thomas, 1930s; 17 (Box 1556)
    - Caption: August 21, 1938. SENATOR POPE GUEST AT SUMMER WHITE HOUSE. Pawling, N.Y. - President Roosevelt with Sen. James P. Pope (left), administration supporter recently defeated in the Idaho primaries for re-nomination, as they watched a game between Lowell Thomas's "Nine Old Men" and the "White House Purgers" here, August 21. Senator Pope may run as an independent. He told newsmen he and the President touched briefly on the possibility of his re-entering the field, 1
    - Note: DEFEATED IDAHO SENATOR DISCUSSES FUTURE PLANS WITH THE PRESIDENT, HYDE PARK, N.Y. - Lowell Thomas, author and radio commentator; Senator James J. Pope of Idaho, and President Roosevelt, photographed (left to right) after attending a baseball game between Mr. Thomas's "Nine Old Men," and the "New Deal Purgers," composed of White House correspondents, photographers and Secret Service Agents, near here on August 21. Both before and after the game, the Chief Executive and the Senator conferred on the advisability of the latter running independently against Representative D. Worth Clark, the choice of the Democratic Party for Senate, 2
    - [left to right: Senator James P. Pope, President Franklin Delano Roosevelt, Lowell Thomas], 3
    - FDR and LT between innings at one of their ball games, LT's "9 Old Men" versus FDR's "Roosevelt Packers". It was an annual series for which LT built a special ball park; Senator James Pope (Idaho), FDR, LT, 4
    - Verso: FDR and LT between innings at one of their ball games, LT's "9 Old Men" versus FDR's "Roosevelt Packers". It was an annual series for which LT built a special ball park; Senator James Pope (Idaho), FDR, LT, 4-verso
    - [President Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Lowell Thomas], 5
    - [President Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Lowell Thomas], 6
    - [President Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Lowell Thomas], 7
    - [President Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Lowell Thomas, signed by L.T.], 8
    - [President Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Lowell Thomas], 9
    - [President Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Lowell Thomas], 10
    - [President Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Lowell Thomas], 11
    - [President Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Lowell Thomas], 12
    - Caption: August 21, 1938. THE PRESIDENT IS SERENADED. Pawling, N.Y. - A feature of the soft ball game here, Aug. 21, between Lowell Thomas's "Nine Old Men" and the "White House Purgers", consisting of correspondents, cameramen, and secret service operatives, was this hillbilly band [Maine Lumberjacks]. They are shown here demonstrating their talents for President Roosevelt who also witnessed the ball game. Standing by in bathing suit is Lowell Thomas, 13
    - [Franklin Delano Roosevelt in car with Lowell Thomas and musicians], 14
    - [Franklin Delano Roosevelt in car with Lowell Thomas and musicians], 15
    - Spectators at Nine Old Men, White House Purgers game, Right to left, Eleanor Roosevelt, Cynic [Westbrook] Pegler, George Bye, Ty Cobb, 16
    - Note: A group of unknown* spectators wildly applauding one of the Nine Old Men, in the annual game with the White House Purgers. *Right to left: The First Lady, Cynic [Westbrook] Pegler, Softball Manager George Bye, and Deems (Ty Cobb) Taylor, 17
    - [red profile of Franklin Delano Roosevelt in car with Lowell Thomas standing], 18
  - Subject files: The Rose Bowl [Seven Wonders of the World float], circa 1956; 18 (Box 1556)
    - Note: LT on Cinerama float in Pasadena Rose Bowl Parade - 40,000 orchids on the float, 1
    - LT on Cinerama float in Pasadena Rose Bowl Parade - 40,000 orchids on the float, 2
    - LT on Cinerama float in Pasadena Rose Bowl Parade - 40,000 orchids on the float, 3
    - LT on Cinerama float in Pasadena Rose Bowl Parade - 40,000 orchids on the float, 4
    - LT on Cinerama float in Pasadena Rose Bowl Parade - 40,000 orchids on the float, 5
    - LT on Cinerama float in Pasadena Rose Bowl Parade - 40,000 orchids on the float, 6
    - LT on Cinerama float in Pasadena Rose Bowl Parade - 40,000 orchids on the float, 7
  - Subject files: Salute to Lowell Thomas dinner, 1965 November 22; 19 (Box 1556)
    - Note: SALUTE TO LOWELL THOMAS - NEW YORK: At a ceremony held at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel here Lowell Thomas was presented with the New York City Bronze Medal. Among those present were: Governor [Nelson] Rockefeller, Thomas Dewey, Edward Sweeney, President of The Explorers Club; Richard Patterson, NYC Chief of Protocol; James G. Stahlman, publisher of the Nashville Banner; and Colonel Bernt Balchen, Arctic flier (11/22/1965), 1
    - [Lowell Thomas at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel being presented with the New York City Bronze Medal], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel where he was presented with the New York City Bronze Medal], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel where he was presented with the New York City Bronze Medal], 4
    - [Two speakers at the ceremony presenting Lowell Thomas with the New York City Bronze Medal], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and two others applauding at a ceremony honoring Lowell Thomas at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and two others applauding at a ceremony honoring Lowell Thomas at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas applauding at the ceremony held at Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 8
    - [Two men standing at the podium at a ceremony held at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas and others at the ceremony presenting Lowell Thomas with the New York City Bronze Medal], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas standing to receive the New York City Bronze Medal], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving the New York City Bronze Medal], 12
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving the New York City Bronze Medal at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 13
    - [Man at the podium presenting an award to Lowell Thomas], 14
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving his awards], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving awards at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving awards at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas holding up an award], 17
    - [Lowell Thomas holding up an award], 18
    - [Two men shaking hands and Lowell Thomas], 19
    - [Lowell thomas and three other men talking], 20
    - [Lowell Thomas and three other men talking], 21
    - [Lowell Thomas making a face at a man], 22
    - [Lowell Thomas making a face at a man], 23
    - [no description], 24
    - Arthur Godfrey and L.T., 25
    - Verso: Arthur Godfrey and L.T., 25-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to a man], 26
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with two men], 27
    - [Lowell Thoms standing with a group at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 28
    - Lowell Thomas talking to people at a banquet], 29
    - [Two men talking at a table], 30
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with others at a banquet table], 31
    - [Lowell Thomas talking with guests at a banquet table], 32
    - [A woman talking to Lowell Thomas], 33
    - [People talking at a banquet table], 34
    - [People talking at a banquet at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 35
    - [Guests chatting at a cocktail table], 36
    - [Three men talking over dessert], 37
    - [Lowell Thomas and two others], 38
    - [Photographs of Lowell Thomas receiving awards at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 39
    - [Photographs of Lowell Thomas talking with guests], 40
    - [Photographs of Lowell Thomas talking with guests and receiving his awards at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 41
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to a man at an award banquet at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 42
  - Subject files: Schemmer wedding [color photographs], undated; 20 (Box 1556)
    - [The Schemmer wedding], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking to Mr. and Mrs. Schemmer], 2
    - [The Schemmer wedding], 3
    - Note: [note that was with photographs], 4
  - Subject files: Philip Schneidermann, undated; 21 (Box 1556)
    - [Philip Schneidermann on the telephone], 1
  - Subject files: William Simon, undated; 22 (Box 1556)
    - Note: [Letter to William Simon from Lowell Thomas concerning photographs], 1
    - [William Simon with Lowell Thomas, Jr.], 2
    - [William Simon with Lowell Thomas, Jr.], 3
  - Subject files: Sketches [photographs only], undated; 23 (Box 1556)
    - [sketch of four men], 1
    - [sketch of Lowell Thomas], 2
    - [sketch of Lowell Thomas], 3
    - Caption: Here s to you! [signed] Lowell Thomas [sketch of Lowell Thomas], 4
    - [sketch of Lowell Thomas], 5
  Box 1557 - Box 1560
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1561 - Box 1565
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6